Finding Aid for Clark J. Adams Papers 1920-1983
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Clark J. Adams Papers 1920-1983
Adams, Clark J., 1904-1981.
Attorney, Michigan State Representative, Justice of the Michigan Supreme Court; biographical information, topical files, and visual materials
88372 Aa 2
1 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Adeline Adams, wife of Clark J. Adams on October 8, 1987. (Donor No. 600 ). Additional materials came in 1998.
The collection is open for research.
Clark J. Adams was born on Silver Lake in Waterford Township Michigan on June 24, 1904. He received both his bachelor and Juris Doctor degrees from the University of Michigan in 1925 and 1927, respectively. Following graduation, Adams went into partnership with C. Bryan Kinney. This lasted until 1956 when he was appointed to the Circuit Court.
A long and fruitful interest in public legal service began in 1930 when Adams ran for the office of prosecuting attorney for Oakland County. From 1937 to 1945 he served Oakland County as State Representative, earning the respect of his colleagues and constituents alike. Adams was legal advisor to G. Mennen Williams from 1949 to 1952. During this time, their relationship developed into a close friendship. Governor Williams appointed Adams to the Michigan Supreme Court in August 1952 to fill out an unexpired term. Following a close and highly contested race, he left the Supreme Court in April 1953.
In 1954 Adams became Pontiac's Notary Public. During 1954 and 1955, he served on the Michigan Corrections Commission. Then in 1956, Governor Williams appointed Adams to the Sixth Judicial Circuit bench, a position to which he was reelected until his retirement seventeen years later in 1973. From 1958 to 1960 he also served on the Governor's Advisory Committees on Reorganization of State Government.
An active member and occasional officer of many legal associations, city clubs, and charity organizations, Adams was on the board of legal directors of the Oakland First Federal Savings Bank and Trust and on the advisory board of the Michigan State University-Oakland Foundation, which later became Oakland University.
While at the University of Michigan, Adams met his wife, Adeline Clark, a fellow student. The two were married on June 22, 1929. They had a son, Clark J. Adams, Jr. and two daughters, Dorothy and Janet. Adams died on September 26, 1981.
The papers of Clark J. Adams are arranged into three series: Biographical, Topical, and Visual Materials. The papers relate to his career as an attorney and public servant.
Subjects:
Adams, Clark J., 1904-1981.; Judges--Michigan.; Lawyers--Michigan.; Michigan. Supreme Court.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Adams, Adeline B.; Adams, Clark J., 1904-1981.; Clothing and dress.; Courtrooms.; Government officials.; Lawyers' Club (University of Michigan); Politicians' wives.; Pontiac Silverdome (Pontiac, Mich.); Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Williams, G. Mennen, Mrs.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Biographical
  The Biographical series located at the beginning of the collection offers a general overview of Adams' life.
  - Clark J. Adams 1920-1983 (Box 1)
  - Family 1940-1982 (Box 1)
- Topical
  Topical Files are arranged by the position or responsibility performed by Adams. Adams' legal career is especially well represented in the Circuit Court and Supreme Court files with newspaper clipping providing more thorough coverage of his court life than his correspondence. Also of interest are the files titled Legal Advisor to Governor G.M. Williams and Miscellaneous Correspondence as they document the relationship, both personal and professional, between Adams and Williams. The Michigan State University-Oakland Foundation series traces the early development of Oakland University.
  - American Cancer Society, correspondence and clippings January-April 1958 (Box 1)
  - Auditor General, clippings 1944 (Box 1)
  - Circuit Court
    - Clippings 1953-1973 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence June 1955-September 1963 (Box 1)
  - Club Memberships 1940-1975 (Box 1)
  - Constitutional Convention Citizens' Advisory Committee
    - Minutes April 1961-June 1961 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence June-September 1961 (Box 1)
  - Governor's Advisory Committee on Reorganization of State Government
    - Minutes 1958-1962 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence
      - 1958-1959 (Box 1)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 1)
    - Reports and Recommendations 1958-1961 (Box 1)
  - Greater Pontiac Area Advisory Council, correspondence June-December 1957, undated (Box 1)
  - Legal Advisor to Governor G.M. Williams
    - Clippings 1949-1973, undated (Box 1)
    - Correspondence February 1949-December 1955 (Box 1)
    - Interviews July 1949-October 1951 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Corrections Commission, correspondence and clippings April 1955-April 1959 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Judges Association, correspondence and clippings April 1963-September 1967 (Box 1)
  - Michigan State Bar Association, correspondence March 1962-September 1962 (Box 1)
  - Michigan State Representative
    - Clippings 1936-1952 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence
      - 1941 (Box 1)
      - 1942 (Box 1)
      - 1943 (Box 1)
      - 1944-1946 (Box 1)
    - Election Certificates 1936-1940 (Box 1)
  - Michigan State University-Oakland Foundation January 1937-July 1963, undated (Box 1)
  - Michigan Supreme Court
    - Clippings 1952-1953 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence July 1952-February 1964 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Traffic Safety Federation, correspondence January 1952-March 1953 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence July 1938-September 1978 (Box 1)
  - Notary Public, correspondence January 1954 (Box 1)
  - Oakland County Bar Association, correspondence and clippings 1934-December 1970 (Box 1)
  - Oakland County-Cauca Valley Alliance Committee, correspondence October 1963-February 1965 (Box 1)
  - Oakland County Committee for Mental Health, correspondence February-June 1955 (Box 1)
  - Oakland County Law Library, correspondence and clippings April-May 1976 (Box 1)
  - Oakland First Federal Savings Bank and Trust, clippings January 1934-1973, undated (Box 1)
  - Pontiac Area Community Council, clippings 1957-1959 (Box 1)
  - Pontiac Stadium Building Authority, correspondence January 1980-February 1981 (Box 1)
  - Prosecuting Attorney 1930 (Box 1)
  - Retirement, correspondence and clippings January 1973-May 1978 (Box 1)
  - United Fund, correspondence and clippings August 1958-January 1959 (Box 1)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials series includes photographs and a videotape of a ceremony honoring Adams.
  - Portraits 1920s-1970s (Box 1)
    (photos of Adams with other public figures, including G. Mennen Williams)
  - Videotape entitled "An Evening Honoring Judge Clark J. Adams," April 19, 1973, 1/2 in. videotape (Box 1)